<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tinnicure</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="mechoftin">Mechanism of Tinnitus</string>
    <string name="cochlea">The ear is a fairly complex organ that converts sound waves
into brain signals. Cochlea (inner ear hearing organ), is a
snail like structure that does this conversion. The cochlea
works by transmitting different frequencies from the point
where it receives the frequency to the corresponding point in
the brain. The brain and cochlea are arranged exactly alike,
with the frequencies (pitches) that are next to each other on
the cochlea being exactly next to each other in the brain as
well.</string>
    <string name="ear_2">Tinnitus is caused when a particular frequency range in the
cochlea is damaged and no longer sends information to the
brain. This may seem strange at first as tinnitus is caused
by the brain NOT receiving signals rather than receiving too
much.</string>
    <string name="brain">Your brain is incredible and is very, very good at reusing
space. For example, if you are blind your brain will often
convert the areas traditionally used for image processing to
instead process extra audio, smell, and taste sensations. In
the case of tinnitus, your brain quickly recognizes that you
no longer have a use for the space reserved for the
frequencies that are damaged in your cochlea, so it reuses
the space for other frequencies. The frequencies near the
damaged frequencies are given extra processing power. So
they become better at detecting patterns and also tend to
spontaneously be more active. Unfortunately, that means
they create the perception of the sound by having too much
activity. The rest of the brain sees that there is activity in the
hearing part and it assumes there is a sound there. This
creates the perception of ringing.</string>
    <string name="help">This is where sound therapy can help.</string>
    <string name="goal">Goals of Sound Therapy</string>
    <string name="soundther">•Sound therapy in tinnitus
management is the strategy of
presenting an external sound to
mask the perceived sound in
the ear, tinnitus.\n\n•Listening to sound therapy will
make your tinnitus less
noticeable. Using sound
therapy in the long term is
thought to potentially rewire the
pathological neuronal pathways
that are responsible for the
perception of tinnitus.</string>
    <string name="types">Types of Sound Therapy</string>
    <string name="typesndther">•Generic (non-customized) masking efforts have
presented broadband noises, most typically white
noise. These noises usually sound like the rain or a
fan. Despite being helpful, they don’t allow the user to
hear other sounds because they cover their entire
hearing spectrum.\n\n•Customized sound therapy is tailored based on your
hearing status and tinnitus pitch match. The
advantage is that the amount of acoustic energy
required for masking is significantly reduced.</string>
    <string name="cust">Customized Sound Therapy</string>
    <string name="custsndther">•After you receive your customized sound therapy, we
would like you to start listening to the provided sound
therapy for at least 2 hours a day. You can use it
during the times that your tinnitus bothers you or
when sleeping.\n\n•Please use the sound therapy everyday during the
program. Tinnitus is a chronic condition and
therefore, needs long term treatment.</string>
    <string name="mindful">Mindful Breathing Exercises</string>
    <string name="mindfulbreath">•Breathing is essential to life and you have been doing it since
the day you where born, but have you ever noticed it?\n\n•The mindful breath meditation will guide you through a
meditation that centers around noticing your breath.\n\n•Explore it with all your senses. Become more familiar with it.
How does it sound? How does it feel with each in-breath and
out-breath? Is the air cool or warm? Where exactly do you feel
the breath?\n\n•We will be using your breath as a tool for relaxation, and
something to focus your attention on to block out the many
thoughts racing through your mind at any particular moment.\n\n•Remember like with all mediations, do not become
discouraged if you are not able to focus your mind during the
entire duration of the meditation. With practice your focus and
meditation will become deeper allowing you to experience
more relaxation and control over your mind.</string>
    <string name="homework">Homework</string>
    <string name="mindfulhomework">•Practice mindful breathing exercise during any free
moment.\n\n•At the very minimum practice 2 times per day for 5 - 8
minutes each session.</string>
    <string name="mod8">The last step to finishing this Cognitive Behavioral Therapy is the Homework for Week 8.</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="outline">Tinnitus Education: Outline</string>
    <string name="tinedoutline">•What is Tinnitus?\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; -How we hear vs. tinnitus\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; hearing.\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; -Sounds of tinnitus\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; -How many people have tinnitus?\n•What causes Tinnitus?\n•How can Tinnitus affect you?\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; -Tinnitus can affect concentration\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; -Tinnitus can cause emotional\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; reactions\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; -Tinnitus can disrupt sleep\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; -Why is tinnitus a problem?\n•Is there a cure?\n &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Methods to eliminate tinnitus or \n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;reduce its loudness\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; •Prescription Drugs\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; •Use of Sound\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; -Methods to manage tinnitus</string>
    <string name="whatis">What is tinnitus?</string>
    <string name="tinnitus">•TIN-i-tus is a ringing, humming, buzzing, or other
chronic noise that is perceived that does not have an
outside source. This sound can occur from one or
both ears, or within the head.\n\n•In the U.S., 50 million people have experienced
tinnitus at some point and 10 million people visit
physicians for this problem</string>
    <string name="howhear">How we hear vs. tinnitus</string>
    <string name="soundwaves">Sound waves in the air become transformed into signals
that the brain recognizes as sound. With tinnitus there
are NO sound wave vibrations that cause nerve fibers to
activate. In most forms of tinnitus, it is thought that
nerves fire on their own. The brain perceive these
signals as sound</string>
    <string name="causes">What Causes Tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod1pg4">•When we get hearing loss, we lose some cells in the
inner ear that sense sound. The brain cells that do
the function of hearing, however, do not die. This
causes an increase in activity in the brain cells that
do the function of hearing.\n\n•Tinnitus is caused by a combination of this increase
in activity and usually one of the following factors:\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Stress\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Anxiety\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Fatigue\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Poor sleep\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Depression
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg5">•Factors such as stress, anxiety, depression, poor
sleep, etc. cause some changes in the brain that
makes the brain more aware of the tinnitus\n\n•Since tinnitus is affected by emotional factors (e.g.,
stress, anxiety, depression, etc), management of
tinnitus requires managing any of these co-existing
issues\n\n•This includes, sleep management, stress
management, etc.</string>
    <string name="sounds">Sounds of Tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod1pg6">•Patients with tinnitus often report sounds of:\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Ringing\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-High pitched tone\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Hissing\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-High tension wire\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Buzzing\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Sizzling\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Crickets
    </string>
    <string name="affect">How can tinnitus affect you?</string>
    <string name="mod1pg7">•Tinnitus can affect a person’s life in a variety of ways
Some of the main effects are:\n\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Concentration difficulties\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Emotional reactions\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Disrupted sleep\n\n
        •The onset of tinnitus can be life-altering
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg8title">Tinnitus can affect concentration</string>
    <string name="mod1pg8">•The sound of tinnitus can disrupt work and tasks that
require your attention\n\n•The chronic sound of tinnitus is unpleasant and
cannot be eliminated\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Some people differ in their ability to ignore sounds.
For some, it is easy to ignore, but for others it can
be challenging\n\n•Tinnitus does not make it difficult to hear, but it can
disturb with focused listening</string>
    <string name="mod1pg9title">Tinnitus can cause emotional reactions</string>
    <string name="mod1pg9">•Tinnitus is a chronic noise and can become irritating\n\n
    •Emotional reactions to tinnitus have been reported to
cause:\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Depression\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Anxiety\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Anger\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Frustration\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Worry\n\n•People with previously existing anxiety and
depression are more prone to chronic tinnitus\n\n•The goal of tinnitus management is to manage these
reactions to tinnitus.</string>
    <string name="mod1pg10title">Tinnitus can disrupt sleep</string>
    <string name="mod1pg10">•Many tinnitus patients have reported sleep problems\n\n
        •Tinnitus can make it hard to fall asleep and returning
to sleep after waking up in the middle of the night\n\n
        •The worse your sleep is, the worse your tinnitus will
be the next day\n\n
        •Tinnitus can cause you to become sleep deprived
and make it harder to normally function during the
day
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg11title">Why does tinnitus become a problem</string>
    <string name="mod1pg11">1. Many people with tinnitus report that “it came out of
nowhere.” Tinnitus is a different sound and it can be
annoying by focusing on it.\n\n2. It can be perceived as a threat and keep our
attention. It can create fear that it is a serious medical
condition or a psychological disorder. There are often
reports of “going crazy” or “having a tumor”.\n\n3. There are different reactions to tinnitus. The sound of
tinnitus may disturb one person, but not another.\n\n4. Tinnitus can be annoying because the sound is
persistent. There is a loss of “peace and quiet”.</string>
    <string name="mod1pg12">5. Tinnitus can trigger negative memories if the onset of
tinnitus was associated with a traumatic event.
Traumatic events can include stressful experiences,
severe sleep disturbance, combat, head injury, or
explosion.\n\n6. Tinnitus is an unwelcomed sound and can be more
irritating if it is louder. Those with a higher sensitivity of
tinnitus appear to be most bothered by it\n\n7. The more attention given to tinnitus, the more it
becomes problem. It may affect you lifestyle.\n\n8. Tinnitus can cause a lack of control. People with
tinnitus feel like it is uncontrollable or escape it.</string>
    <string name="mod1pg13title">Is there a cure?</string>
    <string name="mod1pg13">•Curing tinnitus means that the sound that you hear
would be eliminated.\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Unfortunately, there is no cure for tinnitus yet.\n\n
    •There are available treatments to manage living with
tinnitus. These treatments can:\n\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Reduce its loudness\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Reduce the person’s reactions to the tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod1pg14title">Reduce Its Loudness</string>
    <string name="mod1pg14">•There are many ways to try treat tinnitus, but there is no
proven cure\n\n•Some ways to reduce its loudness are:\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Prescription drugs\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Use of Sound\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;•Hearing aids\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;•Masking\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Generic Masking\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;•Table-top noise generator\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;•Music\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Customized Masking\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;•Sound therapy customized to the hearing and
tinnitus profile
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg15title">Prescription Drugs</string>
    <string name="mod1pg15">•There have been many drugs used to treat tinnitus,
but most are based on a trial-and-error process.\n\n•The drugs used are designed to manage other
tinnitus-related problems such as\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Depression\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Anxiety\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Mood disorders\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Lack of sleep\n\n•With this method for treatment, it must be
approached with great care due to potential side
effects.</string>
    <string name="mod1pg16title">Use of Sound</string>
    <string name="mod1pg16">•Hearing aids\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Hearing aids can assist in tinnitus management since
they allow more sound to reach the brain to reduce
the perception of tinnitus, they increase background
noise, this allows you to hear soothing and interesting
sounds, also they can make difficult listening
situations less stressful.\n\n•Tinnitus Masking\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-This treatment method can give the perception that
tinnitus is eliminated or reduced in loudness. This
method can give the patient a sense of relief from
tinnitus.</string>
    <string name="mod1pg17title">Reduce Reactions to Tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod1pg17">•Reducing the reactions to tinnitus is a way of
management. This approach of treatment can help
you better cope living with tinnitus. This includes:\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Psychological approaches\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;•Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy (CBT)\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;•Mindfulness Based Therapy
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg18title">Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy (CBT)</string>
    <string name="mod1pg18">•CBT combines helping patients change how they
think about their tinnitus to help them feel better with
everyday activity changes\n\n•CBT was initially used to treat depression, anxiety,
and chronic pain.\n\n•It is now used to psychologically manage tinnitus by
reducing negative reactions to tinnitus.</string>
    <string name="mod1pg19title">Mindfulness Based Therapy</string>
    <string name="mod1pg19">•Mindfulness based therapy is used to acknowledge
thoughts of tinnitus in a nonjudgmental way and living
in the moment.\n\n•It is used to accept tinnitus by becoming aware of it.</string>
    <string name="mod1pg20title">Can Tinnitus be Cured?</string>
    <string name="mod1pg20">•“Cure” = eliminate or reduce the tinnitus\n\n
        •No cure yet – research underway\n\n•It can’t be cured, but you can learn to manage your
reactions to it
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg21title">Tinnitus Management</string>
    <string name="mod1pg21">•There are 2 components to tinnitus\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;1. The sound that you hear\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;2. The reaction you have to the sound\n\n•To help Manage your tinnitus, you need to address
both components\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;1. Using sound to help reduce the perception of the
sound\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;2.Manage your reaction to the sound that you hear
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg22title">Goals of Tinnitus Management (All Methods)</string>
    <string name="mod1pg22">•Emotional reactions are reduced\n\n
    •Stress is reduced\n\n
    •Little if any attention is given to tinnitus\n\n
    •Tinnitus does not affect any life activities in a major way\n\n
    •Further help is not needed or wanted\n\n
    •These goals can be reached even if the sound of
your tinnitus doesn’t change!</string>
    <string name="mod1pg23title">Sound Therapy</string>
    <string name="mod1pg23">•What is it?\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Sound that helps reduce the perception of tinnitus\n\n
        •How can it help?\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-By giving you a sense of relief from tension and
stress caused by tinnitus\n\n
        •When can it help?\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Any time your tinnitus bothers you
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg24title">Sound Therapy Things to Remember</string>
    <string name="mod1pg24">•Sound therapy is more soothing to some people, and
less soothing to others\n\n•The goal of customized sound therapy is to direct
more sound to areas of the brain that are thought to
be responsible for the perception of tinnitus\n\n•Music therapy is the combination of sound therapy
and relaxing music\n\n•This allows you to listen to music while the sound
therapy is playing in the background</string>
    <string name="mod1pg25title">Martha</string>
    <string name="mod1pg25">•When Martha reads at home, she listens to music
therapy\n\n•The sense of relief she feels from the music makes it
easier for her to concentrate\n\n•This an example of using music therapy</string>
    <string name="mod1pg26title">Background Sound</string>
    <string name="mod1pg26">•What is it?\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Any sound that is neutral (not soothing and not
interesting)\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-For example like the sound of the air conditioner,
dishwasher or talking of others in a restaurant\n\n•How can it help?\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Reduces contrast to make it easier to ignore your
tinnitus (we’ll explain!)\n\n•When can it help?\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Any time
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg27title">Imagine a Lit Candle in a Dark Room</string>
    <string name="mod1pg27">•The candle is the only light in
the room\n\n•There is sharp contrast
between the bright candle
and the dark room\n\n•The candle naturally attracts
a lot of attention</string>
    <string name="mod1pg28title">Turn on the Lights!</string>
    <string name="mod1pg28">•This is the same lit candle, but
with the lights on\n\n•The contrast between the
candle and the room has been
reduced\n\n•The candle is just as bright as
before, but attracts less
attention because now there is
other light in the room along
with the candle</string>
    <string name="mod1pg29title">Same Candle – Different Backgrounds</string>
    <string name="mod1pg29">This same idea works for tinnitus…</string>
    <string name="mod1pg30title">Imagine “Tinnitus” in a Quiet Room</string>
    <string name="mod1pg30">•The tinnitus is the only
“sound”\n\n•There is sharp contrast
between the tinnitus and
the quiet room\n\n•The tinnitus naturally
attracts a lot of attention</string>
    <string name="mod1pg31title">Turn on the Sound!</string>
    <string name="mod1pg31">•Same tinnitus, but in a
background of sound\n\n•The contrast between the
tinnitus and the quiet room
has been reduced\n\n•The tinnitus is just as loud
as before, but attracts less
attention because of the
background sound</string>
    <string name="mod1pg32title">Same Tinnitus - Different Backgrounds</string>
    <string name="mod1pg33title">Tinnitus Contrast Activity</string>
    <string name="mod1pg33">•Spend a few moments listening to your tinnitus
in quiet\n\n•Then, with the background sound turned on,
notice the reduced contrast\n\n•Reducing contrast makes it easier to ignore
your tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod1pg34title">Background Sound: Things to Remember</string>
    <string name="mod1pg34">•Tinnitus is less likely to get your attention when you
add background sound\n\n•You might not notice background sound helping you
right away—that doesn’t mean it’s not helping you\n\n•Using constant background sound over weeks or
months can help you get better at ignoring tinnitus•Never use sound that is irritating or annoying to you
to manage your reactions to tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod1pg35title">Janet</string>
    <string name="mod1pg35">•Janet keeps a tabletop fountain running on her desk\n\n•The background sound from the fountain makes it easier
for her to ignore her tinnitus\n\n•This is an example of using background sound</string>
    <string name="mod1pg36title">Interesting Sound</string>
    <string name="mod1pg36">•What is it?\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Sound that keeps your attention\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Sound that involves active listening\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Some examples include talk radio, audio books,
interesting music, dynamic speeches\n\n•How can it help?\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Shifts your attention away from your tinnitus\n\n
        •When can it help?\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-When you do not need to concentrate on
something else\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-When you want to relax or sleep
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg37title">Interesting Sound: Things to Remember</string>
    <string name="mod1pg37">•We’re all different!\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Some sounds (e.g., talk radio) are more
interesting to some people, and less interesting to
others\n\n•Your job is to find sounds that are interesting to you\n\n•It might take time and patience to find the sounds that
are most interesting and helpful for you\n\n•Never use sound that is irritating or annoying to you
to manage your reactions to tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod1pg38title">Patrick</string>
    <string name="mod1pg38">•Patrick talks to his friends on the telephone to keep
his mind off of his tinnitus\n\n•This is an example of using interesting sound</string>
    <string name="mod1pg39title">To help you come up with ideas for choosing sounds…</string>
    <string name="mod1pg39">•You can use\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Environmental\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Music\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Speech</string>
    <string name="mod1pg40title">Environmental Sound</string>
    <string name="mod1pg40">•Sounds of nature\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Moving water\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Beach sounds\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Forest sounds\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Animals\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Wind\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Storms and more&#8230;\n\n•Manmade sounds\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Masking noise\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Electric fan noise\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Shower sound\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Aircraft noise\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Wind chimes\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Traffic noise\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Radio static\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and more&#8230;
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg41title">Music</string>
    <string name="mod1pg41">•There are many styles of music\n\n
    •We all have our preferred styles\n\n
      •Any music that is neutral or pleasant can be used to
manage tinnitus – as long as it is not too loud
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg42title">Speech</string>
    <string name="mod1pg42">•Speech can be used as part of your plan to manage
tinnitus\n\n•There are many kinds of speech, and we react
differently depending on the type of speech and the
situation\n\n•Some examples:\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Talking on the phone\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Listening to an audio book\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Listening to a lecture
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg43title">Nine Combinations of Sound to Manage Reactions to Tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod1pg44title">You Have Now Finished This Module</string>
    <string name="mod1pg44">•Next let’s take a closer look at an example</string>
    <string name="mod1pg45title">Bob</string>
    <string name="mod1pg45">•Listening to talk radio helps Bob get his mind off of his
tinnitus at night\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-This helps him get to sleep\n\n
        •This is an example of using interesting sound\n\n
        •Tip: It’s best to NOT use the TV for this as the flashing
images can prevent you from falling asleep
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg46title">Won’t Interesting Sound Keep Me Awake?</string>
    <string name="mod1pg46">•Interesting sound can be a powerful way to get your
mind off of your tinnitus\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-This helps some people relax enough to fall sleep\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-It might not be helpful for others\n\n
        •Be open to using sound in surprising or unusual ways
to manage your reactions to tinnitus!
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pg47title">Another Sleep Challenge for Bob</string>
    <string name="mod1pg47">•Listening to talk radio helps Bob get to sleep when he
goes to bed at night\n\n•However, he wakes up in the middle of the night and
has trouble getting back to sleep because of his tinnitus\n\n•He does not like to listen to interesting sound in the
middle of the night\n\n•What did Bob do?</string>
    <string name="mod1pg48title">Bob’s Solution</string>
    <string name="mod1pg48">•Keeping a fan running all night long reduces the contrast
between Bob’s tinnitus and the quiet of his bedroom\n\n•The reduced contrast helps Bob stay asleep all night long\n\n
    •This is an example of using background sound</string>
    <string name="mod1pg49title">Develop a Sound Plan That is Easy to Do</string>
    <string name="mod1pg49">•Your first Sound Plan should be easy to do and
practical for you\n\n•Use sounds and devices that you already have\n\n
    •As you try the Plan, you will learn what helps the
most\n\n•You will get ideas about how to improve your Plan</string>
    <string name="mod1pg50title">Write Down Your Sound Plan</string>
    <string name="mod1pg50">•What will you use for background sound\n\n
    •(examples include Sound therapy,
fan, fountain, etc.)\n\n\n•What will you use as an interesting sound\n\n
        •(examples include audio book, talk
radio, Music therapy, etc.)
    </string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg1title">Physical Activity Module</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg1">•Exercise and physical activity are excellent methods
for obtaining healthy lifestyle and feeling better.\n\n•At least 15 minutes of physical activity every day is
appropriate for maintaining a good and healthy body.\n\n•Good health and mood in turn help you manage your
tinnitus. Regular exercises also help you get your
attention away from tinnitus.\n\n•Before starting a new exercise program, it is
important to check with your doctor, especially if you
have not exercised for a long time, have chronic
health conditions, such as heart disease, diabetes,
hypertension or arthritis.</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg2title">Exercise promotes better sleep</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg2">•Regular physical activity can help you fall asleep
faster and deepen your sleep.\n\n•Just remember not to do exercise too close to
bedtime. This might cause you to feel too energized
to fall asleep.</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg3title">Exercise improves mood</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg3">•A workout at the gym or a brisk 30-minute walk can
help to relieve stressful daily events.\n\n•Physical activity stimulates various brain neurons
that secrete some special chemicals
(neurotransmitters), which in turn make you feel
happier and more relaxed.\n\n•When you exercise regularly, You may also feel
better about yourself, your body shape and
appearance, which will increase your confidence and
improve your self-esteem.</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg4title">Exercise prevents disorders
and health conditions</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg4">•Exercise has been shown to decrease the risk of
cardiovascular diseases. It is also recommended for
prevention of high blood pressure.\n\n•Independent of current weight, being active increases
high-density lipoprotein (HDL), or "good" cholesterol
and decreases unhealthy triglycerides or Low-
density lipoprotein(LDL). This will keep your blood
flowing smoothly.\n\n•Regular physical activity helps you prevent or
manage a wide range of disorders including stroke,
type 2 diabetes, metabolic syndrome, depression,
certain types of cancer, arthritis, and more
importantly your tinnitus.\n\n•Physical activities and meditation techniques like
Yoga help you bring your tinnitus under control and
deal with the stress that comes along with it.\n\n•Physical activity and regular exercise control weight.\n\n
        •Engagement in a physical activity helps you to burn
calories. The more intense the activity, the more
calories you burn.\n\n•It is not necessary to do an actual workout. You can
get more active throughout the day in simple ways</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg5title">Types of beneficial physical
activities</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg5">•Aerobic activities\n\n•Muscle strengthening activities\n\n
    •Bone strengthening activities\n\n•Balance and stretching activities</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg6title">Aerobic Activities</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg6">•Aerobic activities include rhythmic movements of
large muscles. These activities will make you breathe
harder and increase your heart rate.\n\n•Examples: Running, skipping, swimming, dancing,
bicycling</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg7title">Muscle-strengthening activities</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg7">•Make muscles do more work than they do on daily
basis and make them stronger.\n\n•These include activities like push-ups and lifting
weights.</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg8title">Muscle-strengthening activities</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg8">•They can be done unstructured or as part of a game.\n\n
    •It is important to work all the different parts of the
body - your legs, hips, back, chest, abdomen,
shoulders, and arms.</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg9title">Bone-strengthening activities:</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg9">•Produce force on the bones that causes bone growth
and strength. The force is commonly produced by
impact with the ground.\n\n•Make your bones stronger.</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg10title">Bone-strengthening activities
(Continued)</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg10">•Jumping is especially important for children and
adolescents.\n\n•Examples: Running, tennis, basketball, gymnastics,
hopscotch</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg11title">Balance and stretching
activities</string>
    <string name="mod1pt2pg11">•Enhance physical stability and flexibility, which
reduces risk of injuries.\n\n•Examples: gentle stretching, dancing, yoga, martial
arts, tai chi.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg1title">Sleep Problems</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg1">•Sleep problems are very common. About half of
American adults experience it and about 10% have it
as a chronic problem.\n\n•Sleeping problems can lead to greater medical and
psychiatric problems, impaired job performance, low
quality of life, and less well-being in general.\n\n•Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT) provides a safe
and effective treatment for sleeping problems.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg2title">Types of Sleep Problems</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg2">•Sleep problems can be caused by medical problems
(back pain, breathing problems, sleep apnea, chronic
heart or lung disease, etc.), psychiatric disorders
(anxiety, depression, dementia, etc.), drugs (nicotine,
alcohol, cannabis, etc.), environmental factors
(coffee, loud noisy neighborhood, overstimulation,
etc.), or in response to major life events.\n\n•Tinnitus and sleeping problems have a two-way
relationship. Tinnitus can cause sleeping problems
and in turn, sleeping problems can aggravate tinnitus.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg3title">What people do to help with their sleep</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg3">•When having problems sleeping, many people start
with changing their habits. Some read, watch TV, or
listen to the radio before going to sleep. Others
simply do nothing except toss and turn and wait to fall
asleep.\n\n•Some people try over-the-counter sleep aids or
herbal supplements. Some seek medical care.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg4title">Sleep Management</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg4">•Sleep Management addresses the factors that
surround sleeping problems regardless of the cause.\n\n•These include:\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Daytime naps\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Excessive worry about not being able to sleep\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Amount of time spent in bed before sleeping\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Performance anxiety
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg5title">Summary of Sleep Management</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg5">1. Stimulus Control - Aimed at reestablishing the relationship between
bed/bedroom and sleeping and correcting the
sleep-wake schedule\n\n 2. Sleep Restriction - Intended for creating mild sleep deprivation by
limiting the time in bed and limiting the time in bed
for actual sleeping\n\n3. Relaxation Training - Meditative techniques for reducing body and
muscle tensions and distorted thoughts\n\n4. Cognitive Therapy - Psychotherapeutic methods for correcting wrong
beliefs and attitudes toward sleeping\n\n5. Sleep Hygiene Education - Instructions regarding health practices and factors
causing sleep problems</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg6title">Stimulus Control</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg6">•Stimulus control technique has 5 parts. With practice,
of these parts over time, you will gradually correct
your sleeping schedule and form a healthy stimulus
(bed) and response (sleeping) relationship.\n\n•1) Only go to bed when you feel sleepy:\n\n•We might confuse being tired with sleepiness. We
might go to bed early in order to increase the chance
of falling asleep. This is a bad habit as going to bed
before feeling sleepy will only result in heightened
arousal, which in turn will cause more worry and
frustration
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg7title">Stimulus Control</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg7">•2) Bedroom should only be used for sleeping.\n\n•Sometimes we use our bed/bedroom for eating,
watching TV, working, or studying. This habit will form
an association between the bedroom and being
awake.\n\n•Instead, we better use the bed/bedroom for only
sleeping. This corrected habit will form a
stimulus-response relationship, bed=sleep.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg8title">Stimulus Control</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg8">•3) Get out of bed if you cannot sleep.\n\n•As a rule of thumb, get out of bed if you cannot sleep
after 15 minutes. Leave the bedroom and do a quiet
activity. Examples are reading a book, listening to
classic music, or watching TV.\n\n•Do the same for times when you wake up in the
middle of the night. If you wake up and stay in bed,
this might dissociate the relationship between the bed
and sleeping. Once you leave the room, and felt
sleepy again, return to the bedroom.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg9title">Stimulus Control</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg9">•4) Wake up at the same time every morning.\n\n•This practice will help you reorganize your circadian
(aka sleeping/awakening) rhythm.\n\n•No matter how much you have slept, you should
maintain a regular sleep schedule (sleeping and
awakening time) during weekdays and weekends.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg10title">Stimulus Control</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg10">•5) Never take naps during the day.\n\n•Naps might refresh you during the day, especially if
you suffer from sleep deprivation. This, however,
will make it difficult for you to go to bed and sleep at
the desired bedtime.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg11title">Sleep Restriction</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg11">•Sleep Restriction means that you limit the time you
spend in the bed/bedroom to only the time you are
actually sleeping.\n\n•This technique will create a temporary sleep
deprivation which will result in faster sleep onset.\n\n•We will explain this technique through an example.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg1215title">Sleep Restriction</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg12">•Example: Andrew spends 8 hours every night in bed but he
only sleeps for 6 hours each night. He usually
struggles for 2 hours until he falls asleep.\n\n•Andrew’s doctor asks him to use the sleep
restriction technique. He asks him to limit the time in
bed to 6 hours, his “sleeping window.”\n\n•His doctor then alters this “sleeping window” on a
weekly basis. </string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg13" formatted="false">•As a part of this module, we ask you to follow this
technique and limit your time in bed to your sleeping
window.\n\n•The sleep efficiency goal is calculated as follows:\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-(total sleep time/total time in bed)x100%\n\n•The goal is to keep this percentage to around 85%.
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg14" formatted="false">•If your sleeping efficiency is greater than 90% in
any week, you can take an additional 15-20 extra
minutes in bed per night.\n\n•If your sleeping efficiency is less than 80% in any
week, decrease your sleeping window by 15-20
minutes.\n\n•If your sleep efficiency is between 80% and 90%,
keep your current schedule.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg15">•You should never have a sleeping window of less
than 5 hours as it is not healthy.\n\n•Daytime drowsiness is a side effect of this
technique and is usually temporary.\n\n•If your job deals with heavy machinery, motor
vehicles, or any other duties in which drowsiness is
dangerous, do not reduce the sleeping window to
less than 6 hours.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg1623title">Sleep Management</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg16">•As we discussed, bad habits can cause sleep
problems. These problems can be further
exacerbated by wrong beliefs and unrealistic
expectations.\n\n•We will give you some examples.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg17">•1) Some people correlate their sleeping problems to
specific events or causes like pain, allergy, age,
depression, or tinnitus.\n\n•Matthew cannot sleep because of his tinnitus. He
believes that he can never have good sleep unless
his tinnitus is gone.\n\n•While tinnitus can cause sleep disturbance in some,
believing that he can never sleep with tinnitus is
self-defeating because Matthew has little control
over his tinnitus.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg18">•Example 1 continued:\n\n•Matthew does not know that chronic sleeping
problems are not solely caused by an external
cause. This means tinnitus, when associated with
stress, anxiety, or other psychological factors, will
result in insomnia.\n\n•By practicing the CBT techniques described in this
module, Matthew will learn how to overcome or
adapt to it.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg19">•2) Some people fear the consequences of not
having a good night’s sleep. They have concerns
over health effects of insomnia, which in turn
causes more anxiety and stress with sleeping.\n\n•Mary did not have good sleep last night. She fears
that this will lower her performance in the office. Her
excessive worry about this makes her feel tired.
She then attributes this tiredness to last night’s
sleep loss.\n\n•In general, worrying about consequences of
insomnia makes one more prone to have sleep
problems.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg20">•3) Everyone has different sleeping needs. While the
average sleeping time is said to be 8 hours, this
number greatly varies between individuals.\n\n•Jason sleeps only 6 hours a night. He constantly
compares his sleeping patterns with his wife who
sleeps 7-8 hours a night. He then tries to achieve
some “normal” sleep by going to bed earlier, but
after some struggling in bed, he end up sleeping the
same 6 hours.\n\n•Overly focusing on achieving more sleep worsens
insomnia.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg21">•4) Sleeping problems in some people makes them
feel helpless and develop more anxiety.\n\n•Sophia feels that she has no control over her sleep.
She feels that her sleep controls her. She puts more
pressure on herself to sleep, but the feeling of
powerlessness increases every night and now she
fears to go to the bed because “she knows that she
won’t be able to sleep.”\n\n•This way of thinking will make Sophia see herself as
a victim and worsen the duration of her sleeping
problems.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg22">•Example 4 continued:\n\n•Her doctor asks her to “try not to fall asleep when in
bed.”\n\n•By doing this every night she gets a stronger feeling
that she is gaining control of her sleep cycle. She
also learns not to give too much importance to
sleep.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg23">•5) Some people develop ideas on how to modify
their sleep habits. Some of these ideas are
counterproductive.\n\n•One example is staying in bed later in the morning
to compensate for poor sleep.\n\n•Another example is trying hard to sleep by thinking
more and more about sleeping.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg24title">Sleep Hygiene</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg24">•There are certain measures that you can take to
help you sleep better at night. These are collectively
called sleep hygiene.\n\n1. Do not have caffeine-based or other stimulant drinks after dinner.\n
    2. Do not smoke near bedtime or when you wake up at night\n
    3. Avoid drinking alcohol late at night.\n
    4. Avoid exercising near bedtime. Instead, do them in the late
afternoon or early evening.\n
    5. Reduce noise, light, or excessive temperatures in your bedroom.
People generally sleep when it is cooler rather than warmer\n
    6. Don’t sleep with the television on. The flashing lights of the
moving images can affect sleep onset.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg25title">Relaxation Training</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg25">•Certain relaxation and meditation techniques will
help you sleep better at night.\n\n•These techniques are taught in their modules.\n\n•They will help you achieve a better sleeping at
night.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg26title">Exercise</string>
    <string name="mod3pt1pg26">•Self-report sleep diary is a very good tool to
address your sleeping problems. For the next 1
week, please complete a sleep diary and record the
following: each night’s bedtime, arising time,
sleep-onset latency, number and duration of
nighttime awakenings, time of last awakening, naps,
medication intake, and the quality of your sleep.\n\n•Once you have completed your diary, use it to
estimate your “sleeping window” and try to apply the
other techniques taught in this module.</string>
    <string name="mod6pg13title">Thought Restructuring Module</string>
    <string name="mod6pg1">The beliefs we have about ourselves are very
important. They can influence things such as the
kinds of friends we make, careers we work towards,
and our personality. In this module we will try to
identify your thought processes.</string>
    <string name="mod6pg2">There are certain ways of thinking that could make
you vulnerable to anxiety, depression, or anger.
People at risk for depression have concerns about
failing in life, losing loved ones, and being rejected.
Those who have a predisposition to anxiety are
worried about things that can cause them injury,
general threats, and getting their feelings hurt. People
at risk for anger management issues have issues with
humiliation and inferiority.</string>
    <string name="mod6pg3">The goals in this module:\n\n
    1) Identifying the core beliefs that might make you vulnerable to depression and anxiety\n\n
    2) Changing these core beliefs</string>
    <string name="mod6pg45title">Thought Process</string>
    <string name="mod6pg4">•Your thought processes affect how you view the
world. This affects how you deal with different
situations.\n\n•Thought processes make us pay more attention to
some things more than others. If your thought
process is focused on success, you tend to focus
more on what you have succeeded in life. You think
about the games you have won, the awards you have
won, the good grades you received, etc. This gives
you a positive outlook on life and you continue to look
for successes.</string>
    <string name="mod6pg5">•If, however, your thought processes revolve around
failure, then you remember all your failures more.
You keep thinking about all the games you lost, all
the classes in which you did poorly, and your failures
in life. This gives you a more negative viewpoint of
the world.\n\n•The way you process thoughts also affects the way
you remember things. If you focus on negative
aspects of an event, you will forget all the positive
events. For example, if you keep thinking about
spilling a drink at a party and how embarrassed you
were, you forget the other 99% of the time when you
had a great time.</string>
    <string name="mod6pg67title">Avoiding Thought Patterns</string>
    <string name="mod6pg6">•Sometimes people try to avoid situations in order to
reduce the likelihood of a possible outcome.\n\n•For example, if someone has an anxious thought
pattern, they try to avoid situations that cause them
anxiety. For example, if social situations with the
opposite gender makes them anxious, they will avoid
those situation. Or, if crowds make them anxious,
they will stay at home and not go out. Some people
are worried about being abandoned. They are so
concerned about being abandoned they try to not get
into a relationship or try to break off the relationship
early so they don’t get “dumped” and abandoned.</string>
    <string name="mod6pg7">•Sometimes people are concerned about a traumatic
event and have post-traumatic stress. This leads to a
state of hyper vigilance and constantly paying
attention to their surroundings. They may also try to
avoid people and events that may remind them of the
traumatic event.\n\n•One other way people avoid the thought patterns is
by trying to escape the thoughts by using drugs,
alcohol, stress eating, or sometimes acting out
sexually.\n\n•These behaviors allow one to avoid the thought
processes, but these will eventually come back.
Oftentimes, the addictive behaviors cause more
negative emotions and make you feel worse rather
than better.</string>
    <string name="mod6pg89title">Example</string>
    <string name="mod6pg8">•John recently returned from combat and narrowly
escaped an explosion in which some of his friends
were injured.\n\n•He is constantly aware of his surroundings in the U.S.
He keeps looking in the rear view mirror and around
to make sure there are no threats.\n\n•He drinks alcohol nightly so he can get “drunk
enough to put me to sleep”.\n\n•Many times he wakes up with a headache and thinks
about how he became angry with his family\n\n•This makes him feel worse and he feels more
anxious and depressed.</string>
    <string name="mod6pg9">•Rita is 46 years old and feels like she is showing
signs of aging.\n\n•She thinks, “I am losing my good looks. I am starting
to look old and I’m worried that if it continues, I will be
very unattractive. I checked myself in front of the
mirror, and noticed some lines in the skin around my
eyes. My hair does not shine the way it used to.
There has to be something I can do.\n\n•I spend a lot of time putting on makeup in the
mornings. I saw a plastic surgeon last week about
getting injections in my lips and skin. Maybe I can get
even a facelift. There are lots of young women
around, plenty of competition.\n\n•To keep feeling young, I have to be willing to do what
it takes to get the younger, good looking men. I have
to be willing to do things other women won’t do.\n\n•This type of behavior will not make her feel young,
but may make her look younger. Thinking more about
her positive attributes, her intelligence, her sense of
humor, etc. allows her to feel more confidence when
interacting with men rather than the constant need for
repeated facial injections to fight her wrinkles.</string>
    <string name="mod6pg10title">Review</string>
    <string name="mod6pg10">•Let’s review what we learned in this module:\n\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-We all have particular types of thought patterns
that influence the way we behave.\n\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Some have thought processes which revolve
around success and they remember positive
events. These are the people who see the cup as
half-full. This is how we should strive to be.\n\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-We sometimes we do things to avoid the
outcomes that we are most concerned about. For
example, we try to bury the feelings of sadness,
guilt, or low self-worth by isolating ourselves from
others. Or, in order to avoid distress, we avoid
relationships, etc.\n\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Understanding how our thought patterns influence
the way we behave helps us shape our thought
patterns more positively.
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg1title">Two Categories of Devices</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg1"> Left) Wearable listening devices\n\n Right) Stationary (tabletop) devices
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg2title">Wearable Listening Devices</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg2">The AirDrive earphones sit in front of the ear and allow
        ambient sound to pass, and therefore, allowing user have conversation or watch tv.</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg3title">MP3 Players</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg3">•Very Flexible\n\n
    •Download any sound from CD or podcast\n\n•Normally use “earbuds”
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg4title">Bluetooth</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg4">•Short-range radio technology\n\n
    •Normally used with cell phones\n\n
    •Available with some MP3 players
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg5title">Bluetooth with Hearing Aids</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg5">•Available with some behind-the-ear hearing aids\n\n
        •Hearing aids can receive signal from MP3 player\n\n
        •Also works with some cell phones
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg6title">Satellite Radio</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg6">•Huge number of listening choices\n
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-~160 channels
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg79title">Hearing Aids with T-coils</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg7">•Many hearing aids have a T-coil—sometimes called a telephone program\n
    •Tiny coil of wire in a hearing aid that can pick up electromagnetic signals
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg8">•This is a satellite radio\n\n
    •Instead of headphones, a neckloop is plugged into it</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg9">•The neckloop sends a wireless signal up to the hearing aid\n\n
    •You can plug a neckloop into anything with a standard headphone jack—including cell phones, radios, and MP3 players
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg10title">Tabletop Devices: Examples</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg11title">Tabletop Water Fountain</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg12title">Tabletop Sound Generators</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg13title">Docking Station for an MP3 Player</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg14title">Electric Fan</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg15title">Adding Sight to Sound</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg15">•So far, we have talked about using only sound for
managing reactions to tinnitus\n\n•Listening and watching together can sometimes be
more helpful</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg16title">I am 100% focused on this football game!</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg17title">More Ideas for Using Both Sight and Sound</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg17">•Going out to a movie\n\n•Watching a DVD or a TV show\n\n
    •Going to a play, a concert, or a comedy club\n\n•The content should be meaningful and interesting—to
do a better job of keeping your attention\n\n•Special DVDs are designed to show peaceful scenes
with relaxing music in the background – makes
soothing sound both visual and auditory (see
workbook)</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg18title">Some Ideas for Using Sound at Night</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg19title">“Sound Pillow”</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg19">•Has a cord that can plug into anything with a
standard headphone: iPod, MP3 player, radio, TV,
etc.\n\n•Sound from device comes through speakers in pillow\n\n•Only you hear the sound\n\n
    •Disadvantage: sound is usually only heard in one ear\n\n•Useful if you have tinnitus in only one ear
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg20title">Pillow Speakers</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg20">•These speakers can be placed under your pillow\n\n
    •This way you can use your own pillow not the one
that comes with the “sound pillow”\n\n•The pillow speaker is mainly useful when you have
tinnitus in one ear and you can place that ear on the
pillow</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg21title">Fleece Headband with Embedded Speakers</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg21">•Originally made for skiers, but can be used comfortably in bed\n\n
        •Plugs into any device with standard headphone jack\n\n
        •Only you hear the sound\n\n
        •Sound is heard in both ears
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg22title">Neck Pillows</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg22">•Sometimes used for sleeping on an airplane\n\n
    •This idea came from a Veteran who had tinnitus who
wanted to wear standard earphones at night – he
arranges the pillow so that when he lays his head on
it, there\'s no pressure on the earphones</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg23title">Sound Therapy Takes Time</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg23">•It takes a long time for tinnitus to respond to sound
therapy\n\n•We generally like things to work right away like
medication, but tinnitus is different\n\n•Be patient as sound therapy takes 3 to 6 months to
become effective</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg24title">Changing Thoughts and Feelings to
Manage Tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg24">•This is the fundamental principle of cognitive behavioral
therapy\n
    &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-Describes ways to change your thoughts and
feelings about tinnitus\n\n
        •These is done in addition to using sound to manage tinnitus
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg25title">Avoid Loud Noise</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg25">•Use double hearing
protection when you are
around very loud noise (e.g.,
shooting, flight deck, etc.)\n\n•This means using insert ear
plugs and over the ear
hearing protection\n\n•Use ear plugs when going to
concerts, bars, clubs, where
loud music is played\n\n•Use ear plugs when using
power tools or powered lawn
mowers
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg27title">Standard earplugs</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg28">Left) Correct use\n\n Right) Incorrect use</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg29title">Earmuffs</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg30title">Take Good Care of Yourself</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg30">•Exercise daily\n\n•Eat healthy foods\n\n
    •Avoid/reduce stress\n\n•Make meditation a
routine part of your
day
    </string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg31title">Keep Your Mind and Body Active</string>
    <string name="mod3pt2pg32title">Learn All You Can About Tinnitus</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg1title">Feelings Module</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg1">Why people feel bad?\n
    -They have a negative self-image\n
    -They interpret events and experiences negatively\n
    -Their future outlook is negative\n
    -They believe that bad things will never change\n\n
    What makes people happy:\n
    -They have a positive self-image\n
    -They interpret things positively\n
    -They view of the future positively
    </string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg2title">Character Examples</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg2">-Amy is a happy person and has confidence in herself.
Though she understands that she is not perfect and
has her own faults and weaknesses, she actively tries
to improve them. She has had good experiences with
relationships in the past even though they didn’t work
out but she is hopeful that she will have successful
relationships in the future.\n\n
    -John is unhappy most of the time and believes that
he has bad luck. He sees the future as being dark
and bleak. He has never had good experiences with
his relationships and doesn’t believe that this will
change in the future.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg3title">Advantages of Amy:</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg3">-She feels good about herself, she feels worthy\n\n
        -Her interpretation of events is a positive one\n\n
        -She is looking forward to more happiness and
success</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg4title">Disadvantages of John:</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg4">He has a negative view of himself\n\n
        His interpretation of events are negative\n\n
        He sees the future as being dark for him and he does
not have any hope for change\n\n
        It is obvious that John is in risk of depression and
anxiety more than Amy</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg5">In the next section Amy and John answer questions
about\n\n-Their failing grade on the exam\n-
        About relationships with their “difficult” daughter\n-
        Moving up the corporate ladder</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg6title">Identifying Negative Thoughts and Positive Thoughts</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg6">Please read the character answers to the questions
and identify the negative and positive thoughts,
negative and positive views of the future, and
negative and positive interpretations of events.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg7title">Question 1): Have you ever failed your exam?</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg7">-Amy : Yes 2 or 3 times, I was very sad and
disappointed at first but I found out that it was
because I did not manage my time well. I went out
too much with my friends and spent a lot of time in
the gym. From the beginning of this semester I tried
to focus on school as well as my other interests but I
realize now that I need to spend more time on school.\n\n-John : I am not as smart as I want to be, I failed my
exam 2 or 3 times. Sometimes I think that I am not
suitable for this course. Sometimes I think about
giving up the studying. If it happens again, I think I
will give it up.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg8title">Question 2): Have you ever had
problems in the relationship with your
children?</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg8">-Amy: My daughter always talks back to me. She
fights me on almost everything. But I know that she
is independent and strong-willed. She thinks for
herself and won’t fall to peer pressure like the other
girls her age.\n\n-John: My daughter always talks back to me. She
fights me on everything. She is so disrespectful
towards me and it drives me crazy. I don’t know
what’s wrong with her.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg9title">Question 3): How do you foresee your
progress at the company?</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg9">Amy: I will continue working hard and be a team
player. I can’t expect immediate success but if I keep
being consistent with my work ethic, my boss will
eventually notice and I am sure that I will get that
promotion.\n\n-John: I work hard but I am not sure if anyone notices.
Unless I do something very dramatic there is no
point. At this rate, I don’t think I will ever get
promoted.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg10title">Their Differences</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg10">-People would rather be Amy instead of John. It is
obvious that John is at risk of being depressed and
anxious.\n\n-Amy is much more confident. She has internalized a
more positive view of the future. Most people do not
want to feel unhappy and depressed all the time but
sometimes negative thinking becomes a habit.
Carrying and holding these negative thought make us
more vulnerable to depression, anxiety, and
unhappiness.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg11title">So, Is It My Fault For Feeling Bad?</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg11">Not at all!!\n\n-It is not your fault. It depends on many factors, We
suggest that you modify these negative feelings. By
taking positive steps and improving your skills, you
can change your life.\n\n-Cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) can help people
cope better with their everyday or more serious
problems like abuse, accidents, etc.\n\n-CBT can help people find a way for best coping with
their situation and problems.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg12title">How Do I Become More Satisfied ?</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg12">-You can change your view about the future and about
yourself.\n\n-CBT suggests that your emotions are strongly
influenced by the way you think. Negative emotion
are caused by negative thoughts. Positive emotions
are caused by positive thoughts.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg13title">The Two Kinds of Interpretations</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg13">Say someone is at a party, one of his friend passes
and does not say hi to him.\n\n-Positive Interpretation: She did not see me. If she
saw me, she would have come over.\n\n-Negative Interpretation: She ignored me, she
probably doesn’t like me.\n\n-It isn’t the events themselves that trigger the feelings,
it is our interpretation of the events that lead to such
feelings.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg14title">Example</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg14">-You want to go on a trip with your friends, but you
become ill.\n\n-How do you feel? What are your thoughts?\n\n-What are our characters’
        feelings and thoughts?\n\n
        -Amy: I have not gotten sick for a long time, I am
lucky that it happened now not during my trip . I will
call my friends and explain the situation. Maybe I can
join them later…\n\n-John: This is the worst thing that could happen. Why
am I sick now? I have the absolute worst luck…</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg15">Let’s go through examples that might help
show you how faulty thinking might be the
problem.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg16title">All-or-None Thinking</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg16">When you see things in only 2 categories such as black
or white.\n\n
Example: You see yourself as a failure if you are not
perfect.\n\n
Example: “Nothing I ever do is right.”\n\n
Tinnitus example: “If my tinnitus is loud when I wake up
in the morning, I know I will have a bad day.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg17title">Oversimplifying</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg17">When you interpret one bad event as a pattern that
never changes.\n\nExample: You get on the wrong train one time and think,
“I’ll never learn how to use the subway.”\n\nTinnitus example: “My tinnitus kept me awake all night.
I’ll never get the rest I need.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg18title">Focusing on the Wrong Details</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg18">When you pick out a single detail and focus on it. You
don’t think about more positive details.\n\n
        Example: “I got a 60% on my math homework. I’m a
terrible student.”\n\nTinnitus example: “My tinnitus made it hard to enjoy
dinner with my friend. I’ll never have fun with friends
anymore. ”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg19title">Jumping to Conclusions</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg19">When you think of an event as being unpleasant despite
there being no facts to support it. You assume that you
know what someone else is thinking or assume things
will turn out badly.\n\nExample: “If I go to that party, I won’t know anyone and
will not have fun.”\n\nTinnitus example: “My tinnitus kept me awake last night.
Today I met a friend for coffee. I was really tired and
couldn’t come up with much conversation. He probably
thought I was boring.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg20title">Overestimating</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg20">When you think things are more important than they
really are (such as a mistake, event, or someone else’s
success).\n\nExample: “I forgot to shake my bosses hand!” He’s
going to think that I am unprofessional.\n\nTinnitus example: “My tinnitus makes me moody. No
one wants to be around me.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg21title">Underestimating</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg21">When you think things are less important than what they
really are (such as your success or someone else’s
faults).\n\nExample: “So I got a promotion. It’s not a big deal.”\n\n
        Tinnitus example: “I know I learned how to get sleep
even though my tinnitus is loud and bothers me. Even
so, I don’t think I will ever be able to learn to fully deal
with my tinnitus.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg22title">Assuming the Worst</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg22">When you think something is much worse that it really
is.\n\nExample: “She turned me down when I asked her to go
on a date with me. Holy Crap!!! She will tell everyone.
No one will ever go on a date with me now.”\n\n
        Tinnitus example: “Tinnitus is going to make me a
crazy, moody, deaf person that no one will ever want to
talk to.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg23title">Emotional Thoughts</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg23">When you think that your emotions show the way things
really are. You might think, “I feel it, so it must be true.”\n\n
Example: “I feel like I’m the only one who cleans up
around here, no one ever helps me out.”\n\n
Tinnitus example: “I feel like no one knows what I am
going through with my tinnitus. I feel all alone in my
struggle.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg24title">“Should” statements</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg24">When you say “should” and “shouldn’t” to try to get
yourself to do hard tasks. These statements make you
feel guilty. Also included are these statements with the
words “must” and “ought”.\n\nExample: “I should be eating healthier and stop eating
food I like.”\n\nTinnitus example: “I should be learning how to deal with
my tinnitus instead of avoiding my exercises.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg25title">Labeling</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg25">Attaching a bad label to yourself or others\n\n
        Example: “He lost his keys. He’s so stupid.”\n\n
        Tinnitus example: “I can’t deal with my tinnitus, I’m such
a weakling.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg26title">Making Things Personal</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg26">You see yourself as the cause of negative events when
your are not actually responsible. You ignore other
details.\n\nExample: “My teacher was rude to me because I was
sick.”\n\nTinnitus example: “My tinnitus made it hard for me to
enjoy the picnic. I think I caused everyone else have a
bad time as well.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg27title">Blaming</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg27">You blame others for your problems. You may also
blame yourself for other people’s problems.\n\n
        Example: “I didn’t get the job because you didn’t call to
give me a pep talk before my meeting.”\n\n
Tinnitus example: “My tinnitus wouldn’t be such a
problem if my wife was more supportive.”</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg28title">As You Have Seen</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg28">Everyone has different ways of thinking about events.
\n\nDifferent thoughts lead to different feelings, which
lead us to act differently.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg29title">CBT: Cognitive Behavior Therapy</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg29">We can illustrate CBT with a simple diagram\n\n
Event --> Thought --> Feeling --> Behavior\n\n
Events trigger our thoughts which produce our
feelings which determine our behaviors</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg30title">Example</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg30">You have tried very hard to get that promotion at
work but it was given to someone else.\n\n
You think “all that hard work was for nothing”.\n\n
You feel depressed\n\n
Because you feel depressed, you put in less of an
effort. Your performance declines. You might not
even apply for the next position that opens up.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg31title">How Thoughts Lead to Different Behaviors</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg31">Thoughts: I tried so hard but I guess the people at
work just don’t like me.\n\n
Feelings: depression, anxiety, shame\n\n
Behavior: does the minimal amount of work\n\n
required, not friendly to coworkers\n\n
OR\n\n
Thoughts: I will be more prepared next time, other\n\n
applicants didn’t get it either\n\n
Feelings: a bit of sadness, determination to do better\n\n
Behavior: put in more time at work, come up with\n\n
helpful ideas</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg32title">As Shown:</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg32">Some thoughts trigger negative feelings and some
trigger positive feelings.\n\nMany of us would be very upset at not receiving that
promotion. Trying to handle this situation may cause
positive responses (determination, increased effort)
or negative responses (self-loathing, fear,
avoidance).\n\nResponse to any event can be either positive (useful)
or negative (not useful or even harmful)</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg33">No matter how long or short the event is, it
can trigger strong positive or negative
emotions.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg34title">How Thoughts Influence Feelings</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg34">I think: I will never be happy again. Therefore I feel: Hopeless\n
        I think: Life is not worth living. Therefore. I feel: Suicidal\n
        I think: I am going crazy. Therefore I feel: Frightened, panicky\n
        I think: I can’t do this alone. Therefore I feel: Anxious, dependent\n
        I think: I’ve done this before, I can do it again. Therefore I feel: Hopeful, energized\n
        I think: Nobody is perfect. Therefore I feel: Relieved, less pressured\n
        I think: I didn’t give up, at least I tried. Therefore I feel: Proud, happy\n
        I think: No one cares about me. Therefore I feel: Rejected, lonely\n
    </string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg35">We often believe that we know what other people are
thinking. We have to remember that people think and
see things differently than we do.\n\n
In fact, we have to identify our thoughts and then
examine the facts. If I believe something is true, it
doesn’t necessarily mean that it is.\n\n
Thoughts are hypotheses, descriptions or even
speculations. They can be true or false.\n\n
Many people who are depressed, anxious, or angry
treat their thoughts as if they were facts.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg36">This is an example that shows how the same event can
lead to different thoughts, feelings, and behaviors\n\n
    EVENT: Hear glass breaking while alone at home THOUGHT: Someone is
breaking into my
houseFEELING: AnxiousBEHAVIOR: Lock the door, call
the police\n\n
        EVENT: Hear the window
rattling THOUGHT: It is windy outside FEELING: Slightly irritated BEHAVIOR: Try to tighten the
window \n\n

        EVENT: Someone is
approaching in a
dark, empty street THOUGHT: I am going to get
mugged FEELING: Terrified BEHAVIOR: Run \n\n
        EVENT: Someone is
approaching in a
dark, empty street THOUGHT: Is that my friend
Jack? FEELING: Curious, pleased BEHAVIOR: Call Jack’s name \n\n
        EVENT: My boss is not
responding to my
emails THOUGHT: He wants to fire me FEELING: Hopeless BEHAVIOR: Decreased function
at work \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg37title">Examples of Overlooked Facts</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg37">Negative Thoughts: It is raining outside and it will be
so inconvenient to get home. \nOther Possible Facts: Maybe it stopped raining since I
came in an hour ago.\n\nNegative Thoughts: I am not prepared for my exam
even though I studied a lot. \n Other Possible Facts: I have read the material, gone to
class, and done the work. I am as
ready as I can be.\n\n Negative Thoughts: I will always be alone.\n Other Possible Facts: I have friends and a lot of
qualities that people like.</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg38title">Exercise 1: </string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg38">Lets start with some of your negative thoughts: Is
there any possibility that you can find other facts
related to them? More specifically, facts that might
challenge them?\n\nExample: My boss yelled at me\n
    Negative Thought: I am a terrible person\n
        Other Possible Facts: I didn’t do a good job and maybe he was in a bad mood\n\n1)
    </string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg39title">Exercise 2:</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg39">Please explain the circumstances.\n\n
1) The last time you were very upset\n\nDescription of Event:</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg40title">Exercise 2: Continued</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg40">2) The last time you were very angry\n\nDescription of Event:</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg41title">Exercise 2: Continued</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg41">3) The last time you were very anxious\n\nDescription of Event:</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg42title">Summary</string>
    <string name="mod4pt1pg42">What I have achieved from this module?\n\n
        My thoughts might be more responsible for my bad
feelings than the events.\n\n
Event --> Thought --> Feeling --> Behavior</string>


    <string name="notesEditText">Enter Text</string>
    <string name="mod5pg1title">Changing Negative Thought Module</string>
    <string name="mod5pg1">In this module, we will aim to review how one can
changing their negative thoughts and learn skills and
methods to identify personal vulnerabilities and help
with self-esteem.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg2title">Let’s review some concepts that we have
learned so far before starting off:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg2">1) Our thoughts affect our feelings\n\n
        2) Distorted and negative thoughts\n\n
        3) The way we can identify negative thoughts
    </string>
    <string name="mod5pg3title"></string>
    <string name="mod5pg3">For changing distorted thoughts, we
would like to use methods other than
straight talking.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg4title">Why do we use other alternatives instead
of straight talking?</string>
    <string name="mod5pg4">Sometimes straight talking or personal dialogue may
be difficult. You may be worn out or unable to identify
the negative influences of your thinking. You may be
too tired, too anxious, or too depressed. You may
also become too bored. It is hard work. Other
techniques allow you to get a bit of distance, while
working from a different angle. Remember,
depending on the user, some techniques work better
than others.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg57title">Taking It All Away</string>
    <string name="mod5pg5">•We take much of what we experience in daily life for
granted, assuming it will always be there. Depression
is often the consequence of discounting the positives
in our lives, not appreciating the sources of rewards
that are available. Basically it is about paying
attention to the bad, and not the good in our lives.\n\n•Imagine that everything you have was suddenly taken
away. What do you want back and why?</string>
    <string name="mod5pg6">•Imagine there is a supreme being from whom you
must request the restoration of each person or thing
that you want back. You do not know how many of
these requests will be granted. This being has to be
convinced what you want back is important enough,
and that you will appreciate it.\n\n•You can imagine this being, talk to him or her and ask
him to give you back the people and things that have
been taken away from you. Keep in mind that all of
your material possessions have been taken away
along with your family and your job. Now begin by
asking the supreme (the imaginary one) for one thing
at a time, and try to convince him that you really want
it back and could really appreciate it.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg7">•You should consider this exercise to be invaliding
because the loss or conflict is (real) to you. Losses or
conflicts are real, but so everything else that we ask
you to consider.\n\n•Whether you live out these possibilities or
experiences in your lives will depend on your ability to
recognize your role in existence. Consider the fact
that you are breathing every second. However, you
almost never notice it.\n\n•Now focus on your breathing and imagine that it was
taken away for 5 minutes. Obviously you would die. It
is real, but you did not notice it until you imagined it
stopping.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg8title">Exercise 1:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg8">Consider "What I want back" and "Why is it important to me"</string>
    <string name="mod5pg9title">Looking At It From The Balcony (technique)</string>
    <string name="mod5pg9">Remember an event that made you upset. Try to
examine your experience from third person
perspective. If you were to step back from the current
situation and observe yourself (as if you were looking
down from a balcony), what would you see or think?</string>
    <string name="mod5pg10title">Example</string>
    <string name="mod5pg10">Mary and John have been arguing about sharing
chores at home, both of whom work hard and come
back exhausted. Marry asked john to wash the
dishes and he got upset. Let’s look at their argument
in which John got upset with Mary.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg11">•John: It was not like she asked me, she ordered me.
She does not respect me. I felt really upset and
walked away…\n\n•Right now John imagines that he is watching himself
and Marry in the kitchen. He can hear everything …\n\n•John: Mary was cooking dinner for a while, she had
just gotten back from work. I was quiet at dinner.
After we were finishing the meal, and clearing the
table, Marry said “your turn to wash the dishes”.\n\n•I can hear it from the balcony… Her voice seemed
normal. Maybe I was just in a bad mood.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg12title">Exercise 2:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg12">Please consider several interactions or problems that
bother you and imagine looking down on them from a
balcony. How would you see each situation from the
balcony(negative thoughts, feelings, etc.), or third-party perspective? What would be
the advantages of the added balcony?</string>
    <string name="mod5pg13title">Constructive Alternative</string>
    <string name="mod5pg13">•Anxious, depressed and angry styles of thinking are
often characterized by a rigidity or inflexibility that
locks patients into one response (often maladaptive
one). Constructive alternatives allow us to consider
various other thoughts and actions that might mitigate
our current response.\n\n•Consider the individual who is taking a test, which he
believes he is going to perform poorly on. Using this
method, he would consider a number of reasons why
he might not do well, why the test results are not
essential to his survival, and what actions he can
undertake if he does score poorly on the test.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg14title">Example</string>
    <string name="mod5pg14">•Ellie: I am concerned that Mike and I might break up.
I feel hopeless because I rely on him, I could never
be happy without him. I do not have any alternative
plans.\n\n•Ellie (after using constructive alternative): hmm
before I met Mike I saw my friends more often, I
enjoyed hiking and skiing and exercising. I have
gained weight in the last 2 months because worrying
about this relationship. Actually I like my work and I
like my friends, after we break up I won’t have to
worry about arguing or what is he is doing. I might be
sad, but there are alternatives that I would have
available if Mike were out of the picture.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg15title">Exercise 3:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg15">•Let’s start with one of the negative thoughts or fears
you have. Imagine that this fear actually comes true.
What kind of thoughts would you have and what
actions could you take that might lead to positive
outcomes for you? What could you still do? What
alternatives are available to you?\n\n•Describe your situation and
your negative thoughts (your interpretation). Also consider the
different ways of seeing the current situation
–different interpretations, behaviors, and
opportunities you might pursue.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg16title">Increase Positive Self-Interpretation</string>
    <string name="mod5pg16">•This technique will also help your self esteem.\n\n
    •People vulnerable to depression and anxiety often tell
themselves negative things. You might be used to
telling yourself how pathetic, miserable, and
undeserving you are. In this exercise it is time to
reverse it and credit yourself with some positive
statement to counteract those negative ones.
    </string>
    <string name="mod5pg17title">Example:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg17">1. Negative) Ellie: I am ugly.\n
        Positive) I have pretty eyes and shiny hair.\n\n
        2. Negative) Mark: I am not fast enough.\n
        Positive) I have been getting faster every week.\n\n
        3. Negative) John: I am unlovable.\n
        Positive) My parents and friends love me.
    </string>
    <string name="mod5pg18title">Positive Thinking</string>
    <string name="mod5pg18">•Instructions: On the left hand side of the page there
are 5 places for you to list negative thoughts. On the
right hand side, the idea is for you to list replacement
positive thoughts that you might be able to think of.
Positive thoughts replace negative ones.\n\n•Don’t think it will work?\n\n•This sort of exercise has been proven to work. Simple
things sometimes do work. If all else fails, give it a try.
What’s the worst that can happen?</string>
    <string name="mod5pg19title">Example:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg19">1. Negative) I have been lazy this week and have
not achieved anything.\n
        Replacement Positive Statement) I have gone to work for two days and
completed one assignment.\n\n
        2. Negative) I am useless. I can’t do anything right myself.\n
        Replacement Positive Statement) I went shopping this week, paid the
bills, and made cooked for myself.
    </string>
    <string name="mod5pg20title">Exercise 4:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg21title">Looking at Others Coping</string>
    <string name="mod5pg21">Often times we believe that people who have done worse than
us are off much worse than we are. In fact, this is often not the
case. Consider income. We may believe that we need to make a
certain amount of money in order to have any self-esteem, but
the fact is that there are millions of people who make less than
what we do, and yet they feel fine about themselves and enjoy
many things in their lives. We sometimes focus on how we did
not measure up to our high standards. When this happens, we
focus on the negative things. Consider other people who have
not done as well as you have (or who have experienced a loss
like you have). What positive reactions do they experience in
their lives? How have other people thrived? What were they able
to do that was positive?</string>
    <string name="mod5pg22title">Example:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg22">•Ben: I am down on myself because I did not make as much money
this year as I should have. Many people make less money than I
do, but I expected to make a lot more. Almost half the people I
work with make less money than me. Jane makes about half of
what I make but she enjoys her friends. She has a simple but nice
apartment and she seems to have an upbeat attitude. She is
happy because she doesn’t have my expectations. She can teach
me something about life, how to have fun.\n\n•Rose: I am going through a divorce. I’m a lonely failure. Among my
friends Larry is divorced and Nina has been through it twice. Well,
Larry was actually happy to get out of marriage. He complained
about the financial loss of the divorce, but he’s got his own
apartment, and he started online dating. What can I learn from
Larry? He handled the situation very well. He got a good lawyer
and didn’t sit around. I should do the same things; I should finish
this divorce, should get out, and start meeting people. If people
can handle this stuff every day, why can’t I?</string>
    <string name="mod5pg23title">Exercise 5:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg23">Please describe the conflict, loss of job, income,
relationship, rejection or disapproval on which you
are focused. Then consider any other people you
know (or have known in the past) who have
experienced either a similar or more difficult situation
and coped well in the face of adversity. What could
be learned from them?</string>
    <string name="mod5pg24title">Surveying the Scene</string>
    <string name="mod5pg24">•One additional way to deal with negative thoughts is
to actually demonstrate that your thoughts are
misinterpreted. This is what has been called the
"survey method" by Burns and Zarb.\n\n•How does it work?\n\n•Well, think of the negative interpretations that you
might have about certain events. You might ask
whether they are really negative or not. One way to
find out is to ask others of their interpretations of
events, and find out if your interpretation of certain
events is, in fact, faulty or negative.</string>
    <string name="mod5pg25title">Example:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg25">1. My View) Intepretation: That\'s unfair and doesn\'t make sense.\n
        Feeling: Angry\n
        Behavior: Ignore my wife.\n\n
    2. Daughter\'s View) Interpretation: My wife was frustrated about arguing with her friend.\n
        Feeling: Feel sorry for her.\n
        Behavior: Will try to look after her tomorrow.\n\n
    3. My friend\'s View) Interpretation: Maybe I was lazy.\n
        Feeling: Regret\n
        Behavior: Try to be helpful to my wife.\n\n
    4. Other friend\'s View) Interpretation: It\'s not personal. Ask my wife is she is alright.\n
        Feeling: Concern for my wife.\n
        Behavior: Try to find out what happened. We don\'t normally fight.
    </string>
    <string name="mod5pg26title">Exercise 6:</string>
    <string name="mod5pg26">During the week, find an occasion when you get
overly upset. Write down the event and your
interpretation of it. Also take note of
your consequent behavior. Then ask a few people
how they would feel about such a situation. Note
their reactions. Sample at least 3 people for this
event. Compare your interpretation of the event with
others that they come up with.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg1title">Emotional Processing Module</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg1">•Although cognitive behavioral therapy stresses the
importance of cognition or thoughts in activating or
maintaining negative mood or anxiety, there is a lot of
importance in considering the role of emotional
processing. In this module, we will teach you the
techniques related to activation of emotion through
experimental or emotional focused therapy exercises.\n\n•In addition, we will examine how cognitive behavioral
techniques can be utilized to explore and understand
how we process and conceptualize emotion.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg2title">Let’s start with a recent event that made
you very upset:</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg2">•Think about that event. Certain issues seem to bring
up specific emotions for you. Let’s stay with these
issues, try to focus on situations that represent or
symbolize these issues. Close your eyes and try to
feel the emotions that come with these memories or
images.\n\n•As you focus on these emotions, try to notice any
feelings in your body, notice your breathing, notice
your physical sensations. Are you noticing any
feelings? Any thoughts? Any images?</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg3title">Example:</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg3">•John had recently gone through a breakup with his
girlfriend.\n\n•In addition to being sad, he feels sensations in his
body, he wants to cry and his heart is racing.\n\n•When he closes his eyes and tries to concentrate on
his body he feels:\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;-“...heaviness in my chest and my heart races as if
I am going to cry. But I do not cry because I would
look like I lost control and people would think less
of me. This is the way I feel right now and I cannot
stand being alone. I want her to come back to me,
but I have to hide my emotions because it makes
me look so pathetic.”</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg4title">Exercise 1:</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg4">It is very important to be aware of your emotions.
They can be any kind of emotions–sad, happy, afraid
–anything. Try to notice these emotions during the
week and record them in your emotion log. We can
use this log later to see the range of feelings you are
experiencing.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg5title">Exercise 2: Written Ventilation Technique</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg5">•In free expression of emotion, recall a troubling event
and write down a detailed description of it, paying
close attention to the emotions that surface and what
it meant to you. The immediate effect could lead to an
increase in negative feelings. As the negative events
and the memories become more noticeable, there is
often a decrease in negativity and a reduction in
stress within days or weeks.\n\n•I’d like you to think back about the event that
bothered you so much. Try to get a very clear
recollection of the event and the experience you had.
You could take about 20 min and write down all of
your thoughts and feelings about the event.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg6title">Describe your memory of your story in as much detail as you can…</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg6">What feelings or emotions did you experience in this story?\n\n
What thoughts do you have looking back at this story?\n\n
What parts of this story - what memories - were the most painful?\n\n
How do you feel after writing down this story?
    </string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg7">As we remember things that happen, we often hone
in on specific details, and specific things that made us
laugh or made us upset.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg8title">Hot Spots</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg8">•As you recall your painful story or images, try to
notice if any specific details or parts of the story is
especially difficult for you. Notice if there is any
change in your emotions as you might become more
upset with a specific image or detail. You might even
find yourself “spacing out” on a specific detail.
Perhaps one that is too difficult to pay attention to.\n\n•As you repeat that detail or image, ask yourself what
about it is especially upsetting. What thoughts do
these details generate? What feelings?</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg9title">Exercise 3:</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg9">Write down a memory of a traumatic or upsetting
event in as much detail as possible. Read the story
several times, noting parts that are most upsetting,
then go back over these most upsetting parts and
write down any feelings or thoughts that these hot
spots bring on.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg10title">Exercise 3: Continued</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg10">Describe the story or image in as much detail as you can.\n\n
        Which specific parts are the most upsetting?\n\n
        What feelings and thoughts do you have at these hot spots?
    </string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg11title">Identifying Emotional Schema</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg11">When we feel anxious, sad, angry, or confused, we
may have different thoughts. For example, some
people may believe that these feelings will last a long
time, whereas others believe they are temporary.
Some people believe that they should not have
certain feelings, whereas others accept these
feelings.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg12title">Example:</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg12">Mary: I notice that I get upset about being anxious
especially when I am breathing rapidly and my heart
is pounding. It feels like I am losing control. To avoid
losing control, I try to take a deep breath. Then, I
think to myself: “I should not feel this way, I am an
intelligent and rational person. I am in a relationship
and I am doing well at work. I should not be so
anxious. I think that people see me as very organized
and on top of things, but they don’t know that I feel
this way.”</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg13">The goal of this section is to identify and correct
these kinds of emotional schemas (the way we view
our emotions), and to help you experience and
accept these emotions.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg14title">Exercise 4:</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg14">•We are interested in how you deal with your feelings or
emotions. For example, how you deal with anger, sadness,
anxiety, or sexual feelings. We all differ in how we deal with
these feelings. There are no right or wrong answers. Please
read each sentence carefully and rate it, (using the scale below)
as how you have dealt with your feelings during the past month.
Put the number of your response next to the sentence.\n\n
        1=very untrue\n
        2=somewhat untrue\n
        3=slightly untrue\n
        4=slightly true\n
        5=somewhat true\n
        6=very true
    </string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg15title">Imagery Rescripting Technique</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg15">A traumatic experience may persist in memory for
years, resulting in stress, anxiety, and lowered
immunity. Attempting to modify traumatic images by
relying solely on verbal disputation may not
adequately activate the fear structure and provide
you with a powerful enough encounter to the thoughts
and feelings contained in the image.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg16">The imagery rescripting technique lets you recreate
your story in detail, so you can change the nature of
the original traumatic event. It helps activate a
stronger, more competent emotional component of
the self that counters the defeated and victimized
weaker self.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg17title">Example</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg17">•Bruce: I have a memory of my abusive and aggressive father. He used
to beat me and lock me in the basement. He was a piece of shit and I
felt weak and I thought that no one cared about me. My father was
always drunk and there was no escaping him.\n\n•We ask Bruce to imagine his father to be really small, about 2 feet high
and that he has a tiny, high–pitched voice. We can then ask Bruce
imagine himself big, strong, and ferocious, clench his fists, and see
himself towering over his father.\n\n•Bruce: I can see him as a little midget with the squeaky voice,
screaming at me because I am not doing what I am supposed to be
doing.</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg18title">Example: Continued</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg18">•We ask Bruce to tell his father why he is nothing compare to
Bruce.\n\n•Bruce: You are just a drunk, a failure and a lousy father. I went
to college but not thanks to you.\n\n•I raised a kid and I am a decent person, while you are nobody.\n\n
    •We ask Bruce to tell his father what he will do if his father hits
him again.\n\n•Bruce: I will kill you, I will throw you out of the window.
    </string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg20title">Exercise 5:</string>
    <string name="mod5pt2pg20">•Please recall a former traumatic experience and write down the
details of it. Then imagine yourself in a new reencounter as a
strong, confident, aggressive, and confrontational.\n\n•When you initially experienced a trauma or stressful event, you
may have viewed the other person as superior or more powerful.
Write down a detailed description of
what happened, what other person or event looked like,
sounded like, said, did, ect. Rewrite
the story. This time you are more powerful, while the other
person is weak and scared. You are bigger, while the other
person is smaller. You are the one in control while the other is
afraid. Rewrite the story in a way that is going to make you the
dominate one. Then write your thoughts and feelings about
doing this exercise</string>
    <string name="neg_thoughts">How I currently see what is going on (negative thoughts, feelings, etc.)</string>
    <string name="persp">How I might see it from a third-party perspective.</string>
    <string name="the_situation_bothering_you">The situation bothering you.</string>
    <string name="the_negative_thoughts">The negative thoughts?</string>
    <string name="dexcribe">Describe views of this situation. (new opportunities, possibilities)</string>


</resources>
